Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Katherine and today we've got a great lesson for you about traveling
我是Katherine，今天我们有一节关于旅行的精彩课程，
and getting directions.
以及如何问路。
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes we are looking for an address, we are looking for our friend's house and
所以有时候我们在找地址，找朋友家，
we can't find it.
却找不到。
So what do you have to do?
那你该怎么办呢？
You have to stop and ask someone for directions.
你得停下来找人问路。
There's actually a joke in many countries that men hate to ask for directions.
在很多国家其实有个笑话，说男人讨厌问路。
And so this is the women's approach, asking and getting directions and finally finding
所以这就是女人的做法：问路、得到指引，最终找到
your way.
你的路。
So it's a good thing.
所以这是件好事。
That's a very good thing.
这是件非常好的事。
So we're going to jump right into the dialogue.
那我们直接进入对话吧。
Let's see what happens here and if they can find the place they're looking for.
看看这里发生了什么，他们能不能找到要找的地方。
We've been going around in circles for the past hour.
我们过去一个小时一直在兜圈子。
Will you just please stop and ask for directions?
你能不能停下来问个路？
We are not lost.
我们没迷路。
I'm just taking the scenic route.
我只是在走风景路线。
Yeah, whatever.
是啊，随便你怎么说。
I told you we should buy that GPS that was on sale.
我告诉过你我们应该买那个打折的GPS。
But would you listen to me?
可你听我的吗？
No, this is so typical.
不，这太典型了。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll ask this guy for directions if it will shut your trap.
如果这能让你闭嘴，我就去问那个人路。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
Can you tell me how to get to St. Mary's Church?
你能告诉我怎么去圣玛丽教堂吗？
Sure.
当然。
Go down Park Road, turn left, go up as far as the set of traffic lights and turn left.
沿着公园路走，左转，一直走到红绿灯处再左转。
The place you're looking for is the second building on the right.
你要找的地方是右边第二栋楼。
Thanks.
谢谢。
See, was that hard?
看，有那么难吗？
If you would only listen to me more often, you'd be better off.
如果你多听我的，你会过得更好。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So well, the woman was obviously a little bit angry that the guy refused to admit that
嗯，那个女人显然有点生气，因为那个男人拒绝承认
he was lost.
他迷路了。
That's right.
没错。
She's very frustrated.
她非常沮丧。
And this has been in movies and in books and all sorts of things.
这在电影、书籍和各种东西里都有体现。
This kind of story of the man not wanting to ask for directions.
这种男人不想问路的故事。
And so he keeps saying, listen, I've got these excuses.
所以他一直说，听着，我有这些借口。
I'm taking the scenic route, for example.
比如，我在走风景路线。
That's right.
没错。
And that's our first word for today on Language Takeaway.
这就是我们今天“语言小贴士”的第一个词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So as you say, the scenic route, what does he mean by that?
所以正如你所说，风景路线，他是什么意思？
Okay, route is like a path or a trail or kind of like the way that you go somewhere.
好的，route就像一条路径或小道，或者说是你去某地的路线。
So the route to my house.
比如去我家的路线。
But in this case, the scenic route or the scenic route, you can say in both ways, is
但在这里，scenic route或the scenic route，两种说法都可以，指的是
the most beautiful way to go.
最美丽的路线。
It's usually the longer one.
通常也是更长的路线。
Yeah.
是的。
So you can say, oh, it's just the scenic route.
所以你可以说，哦，只是风景路线。
It's not really true.
这不一定是真的。
It's just the longer route.
只是更长的路线。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So that's the excuse that he's giving her.
所以这就是他给她的借口。
He's like, no, I'm not lost.
他说，不，我没迷路。
We're taking longer because, well, we're taking the beautiful route.
我们走得更长是因为，嗯，我们在走美丽的路线。
All right, with all the trees and the animals and the lakes.
有树、动物和湖泊。
No, I don't.
不，我不信。
I don't buy it.
我不买账。
I don't believe this.
我不相信这个。
That's right.
没错。
I don't believe it.
我不信。
Whatever.
随便吧。
You know what?
你知道吗？
We need a GPS.
我们需要一个GPS。
Okay, GPS, global positioning system.
好的，GPS，全球定位系统。
So many people have these in their cars these days.
现在很多人车里都有这个。
This is like an electronic map that will use your location to show you where to go.
这就像一个电子地图，会根据你的位置告诉你往哪走。
It's very useful.
非常有用。
And especially in places like the United States that have streets that are clearly marked
尤其是在像美国这样的地方，街道标记清晰，
and it's just a little bit easier to get around.
出行稍微容易一些。
You can just get in your car, type in the address you want to go to and the thing talks
你只需上车，输入你想去的地址，然后这个东西会
to you.
跟你说话。
It says turn left, go straight, turn right.
它会说左转、直行、右转。
Creepy.
有点诡异。
So this is a very useful device.
所以这是一个非常有用的设备。
It's like a computer that you use in your computer, a GPS.
它就像一台你用在电脑里的电脑，一个GPS。
All right, so she's talking about the GPS and then at the end of that line, she says,
好了，她正在谈论GPS，然后在那句话的结尾，她说，
this is so typical.
这太典型了。
So what?
那又怎样？
Getting lost.
迷路。
All right, getting lost is so typical.
好了，迷路太典型了。
So something that is typical is common.
所以典型的东西就是常见的。
This is so normal.
这太正常了。
This is so typical.
这太典型了。
This is so something you normally do.
这是你通常做的事情。
So what other examples could we give with the word typical?
那么，我们还能用“典型”这个词举出什么其他例子呢？
Something that is typical?
什么是典型的东西？
Okay, well, you can have a behavior like this.
好吧，你可以有这样的行为。
What he did was typical.
他做的事很典型。
We can also say, in my typical Saturday, I wake up late and drink a coffee and take a
我们也可以说，在我典型的星期六，我晚起，喝杯咖啡，然后小睡
nap.
一会儿。
Okay, cool.
好的，不错。
So it's common, it's regular, it's frequent maybe.
所以它是常见的、常规的，也许频繁的。
That's right.
没错。
Or you go out to dinner and your friend is late.
或者你出去吃饭，你的朋友迟到了。
You say, oh, this is so typical of him.
你说，哦，这太典型了，他就是这样。
Right, he's always late.
对，他总是迟到。
Very good.
非常好。
All right, and we have one last set of words here.
好了，我们还有最后一组词。
And when the guy was giving him instructions, he said, you know what, go left, go right,
当那个人给他指路时，他说，你知道吗，向左走，向右走，
whatever.
随便。
And then he said, until you reach the set of traffic lights.
然后他说，直到你到达那组红绿灯。
So what is a traffic light?
那么什么是红绿灯？
Well, you know what a light is.
嗯，你知道什么是灯。
You know what traffic is.
你知道什么是交通。
Traffic is cars driving on the road, trucks, things like that.
交通就是路上行驶的汽车、卡车之类的东西。
So traffic light is a special light with three colors, red, yellow, and green.
所以红绿灯是一种特殊的灯，有三种颜色：红、黄、绿。
And it tells you if you can stop or go.
它告诉你是否可以停车或通行。
So they're also called stop lights, right?
所以它们也叫停车灯，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So stop lights and traffic lights is the same thing.
所以停车灯和红绿灯是同一个东西。
Usually they hang from above the street.
通常它们悬挂在街道上方。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
Words and phrases there.
那里有单词和短语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in just a little bit.
我们为什么不重新听一遍我们的对话，我们一会儿就回来。
We've been going around in circles for the past hour.
我们过去一个小时一直在兜圈子。
Will you just please stop and ask for directions?
你能不能停下来问个路？
We are not lost.
我们没有迷路。
I'm just taking the scenic route.
我只是在走风景路线。
Yeah, whatever.
是啊，随便吧。
I told you we should buy that GPS that was on sale.
我告诉过你我们应该买那个打折的GPS。
But would you listen to me?
但你听我的吗？
No, this is so typical.
不，这太典型了。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll ask this guy for directions if it will shut your trap.
如果这能让你闭嘴，我就去问那个人路。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
Can you tell me how to get to St. Mary's Church?
你能告诉我怎么去圣玛丽教堂吗？
Sure.
当然。
Go down Park Road, turn left, go up as far as the set of traffic lights and turn left.
沿着公园路走，左转，一直走到红绿灯处，然后左转。
The place you're looking for is the second building on the right.
你要找的地方是右边第二栋楼。
Thanks.
谢谢。
See, was that hard?
看，这难吗？
If you would only listen to me more often, you'd be better off.
如果你能多听我的话，你会过得更好。
All right, we've got some great phrases coming up in Fluency Builder.
好了，我们在流利度构建器中有一些很棒的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So the first phrase that we're going to look at is what the wife said at the very beginning.
所以我们要看的第一个短语是妻子一开始说的。
She said, we have been going around in circles for the past hour.
她说，我们过去一个小时一直在兜圈子。
Going around in circles.
兜圈子。
So we could say we've been driving in circles.
所以我们可以说我们一直在开车兜圈子。
In circles means you've been making the same route over and over and over again.
兜圈子意味着你一遍又一遍地走同一条路线。
You keep seeing the same house, the same tree, the same house, the same tree.
你一直看到同一栋房子、同一棵树、同一栋房子、同一棵树。
So this means we're not going anywhere.
所以这意味着我们哪儿也没去。
You could also say, Marco, I wish you had brought the map.
你也可以说，马可，我希望你带了地图。
We've been walking in circles for two hours.
我们已经走了两个小时圈子了。
Okay, cool.
好的，不错。
So you can use it if you're driving or if you're walking in any situation like that.
所以如果你在开车或走路，任何类似的情况下都可以用。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Okay, good.
好的，很好。
All right, so going around in circles.
好了，所以是兜圈子。
Now, moving on, the guy was a little bit irritated with her and he said something that's a little
现在，继续，那个男人对她有点恼火，他说了一些有点
bit impolite.
不礼貌的话。
He said, you know what?
他说，你知道吗？
I'm going to ask for directions if it will shut your trap.
如果这能让你闭嘴，我就去问路。
Impolite, this is rude.
不礼貌，这很粗鲁。
Yeah, this is very rude.
是的，这非常粗鲁。
So be careful when you use this.
所以使用时要小心。
You can say, hey, shut your trap.
你可以说，嘿，闭上你的嘴。
Okay, so shut means to close.
好，shut 意思是关闭。
But trap, this is your mouth.
但 trap，这是你的嘴巴。
Okay.
好。
So your mouth is a trap.
所以你的嘴巴是个陷阱。
It's kind of like a trap.
有点像陷阱。
In this case, shut your trap is a set phrase and it means shut up.
在这种情况下，shut your trap 是一个固定短语，意思是闭嘴。
Be quiet.
安静点。
Stop talking.
别说话了。
So how can we say this in a nicer way?
那我们怎么用更礼貌的方式说呢？
For example, I've heard people say your yap.
比如，我听过有人说 your yap。
Shut your yap.
闭上你的嘴。
Yeah, shut your yapper.
对，闭上你的嘴。
I would say, can you please stop talking or can we have some quiet time now?
我会说，你能不能别说话了，或者我们现在安静一会儿好吗？
Can we have some quiet time?
我们能安静一会儿吗？
Yeah, that's a polite way.
对，那是礼貌的方式。
The rude way is shut up.
粗鲁的方式是 shut up。
Shut up.
闭嘴。
Yeah.
对。
Shut your mouth.
闭上你的嘴。
That's very direct though, right?
但这很直接，对吧？
Very rude.
非常粗鲁。
Yeah, that's right.
对，没错。
Okay, so shut your trap.
好，所以 shut your trap。
Shut your trap.
闭上你的嘴。
And then the wife said, well, see, there you go.
然后妻子说，看，这不就行了。
We got directions.
我们问到路了。
We're going to get there now.
我们现在就能到了。
And was that hard?
这很难吗？
If you would only listen to me more often, you would be better off.
如果你多听我的话，你会过得更好。
So the guy would be better off.
所以那个家伙会过得更好。
That doesn't really make much sense.
这听起来不太合理。
To be better off.
过得更好。
Okay, so you have to think of this as a phrase, not about the individual words.
好，你得把这个当成一个短语，而不是单个词。
To be better off means to be happier or in some way better.
过得更好意思是更快乐或在某些方面更好。
So for example, if I earned more money, I think I'd be better off.
比如，如果我赚更多钱，我想我会过得更好。
Okay.
好。
Okay, I'd have a nicer life.
好，我会过更好的生活。
To be happier, maybe more successful.
更快乐，也许更成功。
Right.
对。
If you only listened to me, you would be better off means you would make better decisions.
如果你听我的话，你会过得更好，意思是你会做出更好的决定。
You would have a better situation.
你会有更好的处境。
So I could say, if she got a divorce, she would be better off.
所以我可以这么说，如果她离婚了，她会过得更好。
That's right.
没错。
Her life would improve.
她的生活会改善。
To be better off.
过得更好。
This is a great, great, very useful phrase.
这是一个非常非常实用的短语。
Very useful.
非常实用。
All right.
好了。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue for the very last time and we'll be back to talk
那我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊
a little bit more with you.
一点。
We've been going around in circles for the past hour.
我们过去一个小时一直在兜圈子。
Will you just please stop and ask for directions?
你能不能停下来问个路？
We are not lost.
我们没迷路。
I'm just taking the scenic route.
我只是在走风景路线。
Yeah, whatever.
对，随便吧。
I told you we should buy that GPS that was on sale.
我告诉过你该买那个打折的GPS。
But would you listen to me?
但你听我的吗？
No, this is so typical.
不，这太典型了。
Fine.
好吧。
I'll ask this guy for directions if it will shut your trap.
如果这能让你闭嘴，我就去问这个人路。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
Can you tell me how to get to St. Mary's Church?
你能告诉我怎么去圣玛丽教堂吗？
Sure.
当然。
Go down Park Road, turn left, go up as far as the set of traffic lights and turn left.
沿着公园路走，左转，一直走到红绿灯处再左转。
The place you're looking for is the second building on the right.
你要找的地方是右边第二栋楼。
Thanks.
谢谢。
See, was that hard?
看，这难吗？
If you would only listen to me more often, you would be better off.
如果你多听我的话，你会过得更好。
All right.
好了。
So the whole thing about men asking for directions, why do you think men don't like to ask for
所以关于男人问路这件事，你觉得为什么男人不喜欢问
directions?
路？
Well, it depends on the person, but I think a lot of people don't like to admit that they
嗯，这因人而异，但我觉得很多人不喜欢承认自己
don't know.
不知道。
Because if you ask for directions, it means I don't know where I'm going.
因为如果你问路，就意味着我不知道自己要去哪里。
I need help.
我需要帮助。
So this is one problem.
所以这是一个问题。
The other problem is sometimes directions are bad.
另一个问题是，有时候指路信息很糟糕。
I think so too.
我也这么觉得。
Sometimes when you receive an invitation or instructions on how to get to someone's house,
有时候你收到邀请或关于如何到别人家的指示，
they're very ambiguous.
它们非常模糊。
They're like, you know, you pass the dog that's sitting at the corner and you're like, there's
就像，你知道，你经过坐在角落的那条狗，然后你说，那里
no dog.
根本没有狗。
What?
什么？
How?
怎么会？
Yeah, I know.
是啊，我知道。
I know someone who lives in Costa Rica and her address is go down the main street, take
我认识一个住在哥斯达黎加的人，她的地址是：沿着主街走，在邮局后第二个左转，
the second left after the post office and after that, take the right after the general
然后在那之后，在杂货店后右转，
store and 400 paces is the house.
再走400步就是房子。
So there's no address.
所以根本没有地址。
There's no address.
没有地址。
It's, you know, so these instructions can be very confusing, very vague, like you said.
就像，你知道，这些指示可能非常令人困惑，非常模糊，就像你说的。
So I think there's a couple of different problems potentially.
所以我认为可能有好几个不同的问题。
I also heard a joke the other day about a kid asked his mom, he said, Hey, why was Moses
我前几天还听到一个笑话，一个孩子问他妈妈，他说，嘿，为什么摩西
leading everyone through the desert for 40 years?
带领大家在沙漠里走了40年？
And she's like, because he refused to ask for directions.
他妈妈说，因为他拒绝问路。
Funny.
好笑。
I like that.
我喜欢这个。
I was going to say why, because he's going in circles.
我正想说为什么，因为他一直在绕圈子。
All right.
好了。
So if you have any questions about today's lessons or comments, maybe you can tell us,
所以如果你对今天的课程有任何问题或评论，也许你可以告诉我们，
do you like to ask for directions or do you like to figure things out alone?
你喜欢问路还是喜欢自己摸索？
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上告诉我们。
All right.
好了。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Take care.
保重。